ADAPTED FROM THE BLOSSOMING LOVE
BY SUI YU ER AN ON ICEREAD.COM
Because you're from the Spirit Clan,
if you're willing to hand over the token,
I can keep your whereabouts secret.
It seems the token isn't with you.
Since she's here,
the token must be hidden somewhere else.
Didn't you say you wouldn't help me,
and my life or death was up to me?
It's just an act.
There's no need for anyone to really die.
Can't you say something nice for once?
After such a big show,
purposely letting her go,
do you really think
she'll go find her accomplices?
She's made up her mind to die.
We won't get anything from forcing her.
Now that she knows
her identity's been exposed,
she can't leave the city,
and she can't treat her wounds.
She'll have to go find
her hidden accomplices
and look for another chance
to get the token out.
How are you sure she has accomplices?
The location of the token is a top secret,
and there are layers of defenses
inside and outside the Mirage Palace.
It's impossible for it
to be stolen so easily.
If Su Ningzhen weren't the real thief,
then there's only one possibility.
Inside the Mirage Palace,
someone is working
with this Serpent Spirit.
Do you suspect anyone?
For now,
we can only see if Xuyue
can catch up with them.
You must find a chance
to take this token out.
My wound might never heal.
You must help the Master
complete the great task.
This is not just the Master's wish,
It's the hope of our entire Spirit Clan.
You go first.
What are you planning to do?
Are you going to take me
to the Mirage Palace
or the Spirit Management Bureau?
Are you going to threaten
and bribe me or torture me?
I won't let you have your way.
I failed. The Serpent Spirit is dead.
Her accomplice has also escaped.
All I brought back was
the Serpent Spirit's spiritual essence.
You did a good job.
At least you confirmed for us
that she has companions.
What did they say when they met?
The Serpent Spirit told her accomplice
to take the token away.
She also mentioned their master,
saying it was
for the entire Spirit Clan.
Why are you staring at me?
I don't know anything.
Master?
Have you ever heard
of the Decaying Immortal Pavilion?
It's a mysterious organization
that has emerged
in the human world in recent years.
They act secretly,
and their members' identities are unknown.
No one has ever truly found their traces.
But over time,
some information is bound to leak out.
I've heard that to join
the Decaying Immortal Pavilion,
one must brand a special mark
and swear eternal loyalty.
For the Humans,
it's branded
on the spirit platform inside the body,
while for the Spirit Clan,
it's branded on the spiritual essence.
The Decaying Immortal Pavilion…
This name sounds
like it has a conflict
with the Immortal Alliance.
So, the Decaying Immortal Pavilion
has been lying low for years,
waiting to join forces with
the Dark Clan to seize the Chaos Pearl.
Do you think
the Decaying Immortal Pavilion
is the same group
as the traitor in the Immortal Alliance
who sold you out?
According to what the Serpent Spirit said,
the reason they are doing these things
is also because of the conflict
between Humans and the Spirit Clan.
If this issue isn't resolved properly,
I'm afraid things
won't be peaceful in the future.
For now, let's wait
for news from Miss Gao.
First, we need to retrieve the token,
then plan our next move.
No matter what,
the Chaos Pearl must not be compromised.
MIRAGE PALACE
-What's going on?
-What's your name?
-I don't know.
-Wang Zheng.
-Search this place thoroughly!
-Yes!
-Search!
Yes!
-You, go over there.
-Yes!
-Where's the Serpent Spirit?
-Search here.
-Be careful.
-Understood.
She ran away.
She ran away?
With you there,
the Serpent Spirit could escape?
I was heavily injured in the Dark Abyss.
My spiritual power was greatly weakened.
If it weren't for Miss Mu's help,
I'm afraid…
I would have died
by that Serpent Spirit's hands.
That's… right!
It was quite dangerous just now.
Fortunately, I was there.
Had I known you two were like this,
I wouldn't have let you investigate.
Right now, there is indeed something
that you need to look into.
What is it?
MIRAGE PALACE DISCIPLE ROSTER
GONGSUN QIN
Gongsun Qin.
Come over.
Come.
We've already checked hundreds of people.
How many are left?
Only about 20.
Alright.
Next!
I'm… He Qun…
No issues… the night before last…
I… went to bed early…
No one can testify for me…
Gotcha!
No… it's not me!
If it's not you, why are you so nervous?
Your words are all confused.
I… I have a stutter.
The entire palace… can prove it.
But no one can prove
where you were the night before last.
I…
Did you sleep with him
the night before last?
I… I'm his sister.
I received a letter
from home two days ago,
saying our mother was gravely ill.
So, I went to discuss this
with my brother.
Then, what about last night?
What did you two do last night?
I went to the kitchen to steal something,
planning to send it back home.
But I was caught
and was punished to wash dishes all night.
Alright, you can go now.
-Understood.
-He's not the person.
Next!
-Not the person.
-Next!
-I was punished to clean the front yard.
Next!
-Next…
-Senior can testify for me…
Madam.
How's Xie Xuechen's progress?
There were some actions
in the Warmth Pavilion.
The Serpent Spirit
who stole the token is dead,
but we didn't find the token.
Keep watching.
Understood.
What about Qiumin?
She has summoned
all the disciples in the palace
and is questioning them one by one
about their whereabouts
from the night before last to today.
She suspects
there's a mole inside the palace.
Yes. However,
there are too many
disciples in the palace.
She's making quite a stir.
Should I stop her?
No need.
Let her investigate.
The Mirage Palace
hasn't been cleaned for too long.
It's a good opportunity to clean it up.
Go tell Qiumin
to search every room
to see where the token really is.
Do we have to search every room?
Won't this make
the disciples uncomfortable?
Uncomfortable?
I'm not just searching rooms,
I'm going to search everyone's bodies.
Do they dare to be uncomfortable?
Of course not.
I'll go deliver the message right away.
Zai Xi.
Madam.
What have you been doing
from the night before last to today?
Are you suspecting me, Madam?
How could that be?
I'm just asking casually.
I was formulating medicine the other day,
but encountered some difficulties.
So, I went to the library
at night to consult the texts
until midnight,
when I heard the palace alarm go off
and realized
the Spirit Clan had stolen the token.
By the time I got there,
you had already injured her.
The Spirit Clan had already fled.
From yesterday to today,
I've been refining medicine
in the alchemy room.
I only came out an hour ago
and heard about the Young Madam's actions.
The disciples guarding the library
and alchemy room can confirm this.
I see. Go ahead.
What are you looking at?
Your people?
What are you here for?
It's windy here.
I bring you some medicine
to keep away the cold.
I don't drink wine.
Then, I'll drink it myself.
This wine is quite good.
When I was in the Dark Abyss,
we never saw the light of day.
Though there were flowers and plants,
they were all soaked
in demonic energy all day long.
The wine brewed from them
also carried poison.
We often drank poisoned wine
with antidote.
Knowing the danger,
but still unable to resist
the desire in our hearts,
we rushed towards it eagerly.
Now it's fine.
I can drink as I please.
I heard the tallest building ahead
is the Spirit Management Bureau,
the nightmare place
for countless Spirit Clan members.
If it weren't for the Spirit
Management Bureau, this hellish place,
if the lord of the Mirage City
isn't Su Ningzhen,
this place actually
looks like a human paradise.
Why did you lie to Gao Qiumin today,
saying you couldn't defeat
that Serpent Spirit?
I wasn't lying to her.
You were lying to Su Ningzhen?
No…
Not just Su Ningzhen,
but the entire Immortal Alliance.
I don't know who the mole is.
I have to keep it from everyone for now.
Only if I show weakness
will the enemy think
there's an opportunity.
Oh, our Mr. Xie
has learned to deceive.
What's this?
Those close to the dark are tainted.
Fine!
I've misled you.
But what if they believe it's true
and come to kill you?
Then, let them come.
So, our Mr. Xie
is really that self-confident.
But I guess,
in the face of absolute power,
all schemes are useless.
Is there so much to write down?
Maybe you're just used to yourself,
but in my eyes, you're still quite fresh.
What's wrong?
Are you curious about how I wrote you?
Want to see?
Not curious at all.
He's quite arrogant.
HE'S PRETTY SELF-CONFIDENT
AND HE'S QUITE ARROGANT
Today is the ninth of the month.
Sir, it's time for your medicine.
Alright, I'll take it soon.
Greenview Heights has been
out of the Immortal Alliance for years.
You have never been interested
in the matters of the Immortal Alliance.
Why are you getting involved this time?
Is it for Xie Xuechen or…
for that old friend?
Rather than saying it's for someone,
it's more like it's for myself.
I wanted something interesting.
I've been bored for so many years.
Finally, someone interesting appeared,
and some interesting things are happening.
I also want to see
how this story ends up.
By the way,
had the token already
been stolen the night before last
when you escorted someone
back to the Mirage Palace?
-Yes.
-Then, when you saw Su Ningzhen,
did you notice anything strange?
At that time, the Mirage Palace
was busy with the search.
I also asked Su Ningzhen a few questions,
got the general idea of things, and left.
I didn't notice anything unusual.
Sir, are you suspecting Su Ningzhen?
We came here to investigate.
There was quite a stir,
both openly and secretly.
But she didn't stop us at all.
That doesn't seem like her style.
When I looked at Madam Su's expression,
that kind of anger
didn't seem like an act.
Speaking of something unusual,
it seems there's really something off.
CELESTIAL INN
I've inquired about every person
in the Mirage Palace
and verified it all.
I haven't found anyone suspicious.
And I've carefully searched everyone,
checked their rooms,
and didn't find the token.
Xie Xuechen, are you sure
you didn't make a mistake?
There's no mole in the Mirage Palace.
Are you sure
you've checked everyone in the palace?
I'm sure I've carefully checked
every single person.
I even checked Elder Zai Xi.
Except for my madam.
My madam couldn't possibly be the one.
There's one more person.
Have you checked her?
Who else?
Cui Wanwan.
That night when I escorted Cui Wanwan
back to the Mirage Palace,
I paid a visit to Madam Su.
When I left, I saw a patch
of green hooked leaf outside the hall.
I don't know much about plants,
but I remembered it
because the hooked leaf
looked quite unusual.
Also, I didn't see
any hooked-leaf trees nearby.
I was curious where it came from,
but that thought was fleeting.
At the time, I didn't
pay much attention to it.
So what?
Miss Gao, you grew up in the Mirage City,
familiar with
spiritual flowers and plants.
You should know better than us
that the Mirage City
doesn't have hooked-leaf trees.
So, it must have come
from outside the city.
The hooked-leaf plant
has many backward hooks.
It's easy for it to get caught
on someone's clothing.
Before it's picked, the leaf is green.
Once picked,
it turns brown within one hour.
Feng Yao just said
the hooked leaf was green.
This only proves
that someone
rushed into the city that night.
Even if there was that leaf,
it might have been left
by the Serpent Spirit.
We've checked.
The Serpent Spirit
entered the city four days ago.
If it was her,
the leaf would have already changed color.
The token's hiding place is well guarded.
It's impossible for that Serpent Spirit
to break the array on her own.
So, Cui Wanwan
must have come back to assist.
Miss Gao,
when you were attacked outside the city,
it was planned in advance.
You were possessed by the Dark Clan
and went to Greenview Heights,
while Cui Wanwan took the chance
to sneak back into
the city and steal the token.
She tried to create an alibi
and clear herself of suspicion.
These are all your side's words.
Where's the evidence? Where's the leaf?
We already told you,
Feng Yao didn't pay attention to it,
so she definitely
didn't bring the leaf back.
Besides, even if she brought it back,
the leaf would have changed color by now.
It can't prove the timing.
You don't have any evidence,
and now you're just
making baseless accusations.
Cui Wanwan has been
in the Mirage Palace for ten years.
And everything has been fine
during these ten years.
She couldn't have done this.
You've personally inquired and searched
and eliminated all other possibilities.
So, what remains,
even if hard to accept,
is the truth.
-It can't be her.
-What's the reason for your firm belief?
I want to believe her.
Want to believe?
Now, it's the Mirage Palace
that lost the token.
As the young madam,
you aren't thinking
of retrieving the token soon
to make up
for the Mirage Palace's mistake.
Instead, you plan to risk the safety
of the entire Immortal Alliance and Humans
to gamble on a bond of loyalty.
How generous of you!
Do you think we're busy here
just to entertain you?
Looks like Miss Mu
has some ill will against Miss Gao.
Yes.
I don't like her.
I've never liked her.
ELEGANCE PAVILION
Senior,
you're here!
How do you know it's me
before the door is even open?
Because only you
knock like that every time.
-What's this?
-Well,
I just visited the Celestial Inn,
and on my way back,
I specially brought this for you.
Looks delicious!
You told me before
that you suffered a lot
when you were little,
and when you grew up,
your favorite food became sweets.
Thank you, Senior.
By the way, since we didn't find anything,
did Mr. Xie and the others
complain anything?
They said the previous investigation
direction was wrong,
so they need to rethink.
It's really delicious.
Wanwan,
do you think
the one colluding with
the Spirit Clan to steal the token
is really one of our own people?
What do they want?
Is it something
the Mirage Palace can't provide?
Why betray us?
Senior,
they say you can't know
a person from their face.
In this world, people live
for themselves, after all.
Is that true for you, too?
You have something you want as well?
Of course. Everyone
has something they desire, right?
As for me, I don't want to suffer anymore.
I just want to live like this forever,
not needing to be extraordinary,
just being a regular cultivator,
living an ordinary life.
And also,
always staying by your side,
watching you become the greatest
female cultivator of the Humans,
and watching you stand atop the Humans!
Senior…
How come…
I'm so tired all of a sudden?
Wanwan,
I naturally believe in you,
but I can't stake
the entire Mirage Palace and the Humans
on this gamble.
Wanwan, fortunately, it wasn't you.
You should sleep well.
When you wake up,
everything will return to normal.
We found it!
Let's go!
Yan Si, you must immediately
take the token back to the Master.
-What about you?
-I still have a mission.
I must stay hidden here
and cannot expose myself.
Later, I'll pretend to return
from outside the city.
They won't suspect me.
-Hurry and leave.
-Be careful.
Who are you?
How dare you steal the token
from the Mirage Palace?
The Spirit Clan?
Madam.
Seal off the entire city.
No one is allowed out.
Lock down the entire city
and search for the Spirit Clan.
Guard all the pharmacies.
All fire-type medicines
are forbidden for sale!
Yes, madam!
Have you found anything?
-No.
Keep searching.
Understood.
Are you Cui Wanwan from the Mirage Palace?
Miss, don't be afraid.
We were entrusted by Miss Gao
to come assist you.
I see you've injured your arm.
This place isn't far from the Mirage City.
Let me escort you
back to the city for treatment.
Thank you.
Yan Si,
the plan has begun.
The great task will succeed.
I won't let you die in vain.
MIRAGE PALACE
Young Madam,
Mr. Xie has arrived.
Why are you here?
You're not here for that leaf, are you?
I've already searched thoroughly.
Nothing here.
I've also searched the room
where Wanwan stayed.
No token. Please stop suspecting her.
We came here this time
to visit Madam Su.
Hey, you don't have any evidence.
Don't make false accusations at my madam.
She's just too suspicious.
Don't harm Wanwan.
Miss Gao, you're overthinking.
We've already exposed our whereabouts
while capturing the Serpent Spirit.
It's impossible
to keep investigating secretly.
So,
there's no need for us to hide anymore.
Xuyue and I have been in the city
for a while now.
As juniors,
we should visit Madam Su.
What about your sharp-tongued cousin?
And that female guard?
They're at the inn, guarding the array.
Guarding the array? What array?
Though the Serpent Spirit
has already taken her own life,
Feng Yao gained her spiritual essence.
I've been thinking deeply.
Suddenly, I remembered
an array recorded in ancient texts
called the Rewinding Array.
It can be activated within four hours.
When it's ready, we'll place
the spiritual essence into the array,
so that we can access
the Serpent Spirit's memories.
We will quickly discover
who the mole in the Mirage Palace is,
who's behind her,
and what their plan is.
We'll know everything clearly.
Miss Gao, you seem a bit upset.
Are you worried the array won't work,
or are you afraid
we might really find out the person?
Whoever we find, we'll deal with them.
There will be no mercy.
CELESTIAL INN
Come out.
Since you're here, why hide your face?
Why not be honest
and show your true face?
Even if you destroy this array,
it won't matter.
As long as we have
the Serpent Spirit's essence,
we can restart the second, third… array.
Don't waste your efforts.
Look at you.
You're just watching
the show from the outside,
not helping at all,
huh?
The trap was set
right in the spiritual essence.
Naturally, we needed her to get it first.
Why is it you?
-Why?
-I told you,
everyone has something they desire.
What do you want?
I told you before
about my background.
But that wasn't true.
Do you want to hear the real story?
When I was very young,
my biological parents
sold me to human traffickers
who make disabled beggars.
Do you know what they were involved in?
Do you know how cruel it is?
You don't know,
but my biological parents did.
But they still sold me
just for a few coins.
Then they went on to gamble.
They were already deeply in debt.
Why didn't they stop being greedy,
still hoping to turn things around,
and become rich?
But luckily,
two monkey spirits passing by saved me,
took me back to their settlement,
and raised me.
They were kind to me,
and I regarded them as my real family.
But one day,
several injured human cultivators
passed by there.
The monkey spirits are pure-hearted,
so they took them in
and worked hard to find spiritual herbs
to heal their wounds.
But that night,
they set up a Spirit Slaying array
and killed all the monkey spirits
just to take
their spiritual essence for a reward.
Senior, you've lived a privileged life.
Everyone has pampered and catered to you.
Have you ever seen true human nature?
Do you know how vile it can be
and how easily it can be tested?
The real demon isn't in the Dark Abyss.
It's here, in the human world.
Since this world hasn't given
the Spirit Clan a way to live,
then I'll find a new way for them.
Does your new way
mean cooperating with the Dark Abyss
and letting them destroy the Humans?
What's wrong with that?
But you're human too!
If I could, I wouldn't want to be human!
You knew all along
that we've already suspected you.
With such an obvious trap,
why would you still jump into it?
You should understand.
Just like you want to believe me,
but you don't dare bet the Mirage Palace
and the Humans on it,
I'm the same.
I also have something
more important than my life to protect.
Yan Si can die.
I can die too.
But our plan cannot be exposed.
Our great task must proceed.
Luckily,
this is just a trap.
Who is the master
of the Decaying Immortal Pavilion,
who can make you so devoted?
It seems
she doesn't plan to confess.
Wanwan, even though you deceived me,
there's one thing that's true.
All these years,
among all the sisters
of the Mirage Palace,
you've always stayed by my side.
I don't want you to be harmed.
I don't want you to die.
As long as you hand over the token
and tell me who's behind it,
I'll go beg the Madam to spare your life.
Is that okay?
At this point,
you're still willing to trust me?
Of course, I'm willing to trust you.
Turn back.
If… If you want to save the Spirit Clan,
you can discuss it with me.
We'll figure out a way together. Okay?
Alright.
I'll give you the token.
Don't come closer!
Senior,
you're still too naive.
-Cui Wanwan, you're insane!
-Move!
Gao Qiumin, you really are a fool.
All these years, you thought
everyone's respect for you
was because they liked you
or respected you?
It's just because of your identity.
I'm no different from them.
I hate you too.
And that Su Ningzhen,
she controls you at every turn.
You don't even know how to resist.
Someone like you,
still thinking of helping me?
You're not just naive,
-you're foolish.
-Have you said enough?
Yes, I've said enough.
Let's go our separate ways from now on.
Wanwan!
Just being a regular cultivator,
living an ordinary life,
always staying by your side,
watching you
become the greatest
female cultivator of the Humans,
and watching you stand atop the Humans!
She deserves to die.
Search her.
It's alright.
What you're afraid to do,
I will do for you.
What's wrong?
It seems
everything is going too smoothly.
Isn't smoothness a good thing?
Mr. Xie,
thank you all for your help this time.
We will remember this kindness.
Madam, you're too polite.
I sincerely invite you all to be
our guests at the Mirage Palace tonight,
so I can show my hospitality.
Mr. Xie, please don't refuse.
Since Madam invited,
we will certainly attend the banquet.
That's great.
I'll go back to the palace
and make arrangements.
Are you sure you're members
of the Immortal Alliance?
Su Ningzhen looks
even colder than Sang Qi.
Don't speak carelessly.
Why do you look so upset?
Is it because of Cui Wanwan's words?
I thought you only stood with the Humans.
I didn't expect you
to sympathize with the Spirit Clan.
Then, why did you
stop me from killing Gao Qiumin?
I judge based on right and wrong.
It has nothing to do with Clans.
Gao Qiumin's wrongdoings
didn't deserve death.
If you wanted to kill her,
I naturally had to stop you.
So, that means,
if I had more right reasoning,
-you would also side with me?
-Except you.
Why?
Your reasoning
is mostly nonsense.
What's wrong with nonsense?
Nonsense is still reasoning.
MIRAGE PALACE
This time, we've eliminated the mole
and retrieved the token
thanks to your help.
I'll toast you all.
I don't drink wine.
Then, let's substitute with tea.
That's fine.
Please.
Mr. Xie,
you were trapped in the Dark Abyss.
We were slow to respond
and failed to rescue you in time.
Instead, you came to help while injured.
I truly feel ashamed.
You're being too hard on yourself.
But Mr. Xie and Mr. Nan,
since you came to my place this afternoon,
why didn't you tell me beforehand?
The so-called "Rewinding Array"
was just your trick of luring the enemy.
Could it be you two
don't trust me?
How could that be?
It's just that there are
many people in the Mirage Palace.
If we're luring the enemy,
it's better if fewer people know.
Speaking of which,
we only informed Miss Gao
after we set the trap.
Madam,
I don't think
all the Spirit Clan members are--
Enough.
Let's not talk about unpleasant things
at this banquet.
We have homemade wine.
It's made with rare spiritual flowers.
Except for Mr. Xie,
the rest of you should try it.
I've already sent someone to get it.
It'll be here soon.
Please.
What are you doing here?
Zai Xi?
Why is it her bringing the wine?
The Soul-Stealing Gu?
Xie Xuechen!
Elder Zai Xi!
Don't touch her! It spreads easily.
It's the legendary Dark Abyss Gu curse.
Why would it be here?
The Dark Abyss Gu curse?
Madam…